<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<node name="/Status" xmlns:tp="http://telepathy.freedesktop.org/wiki/DbusSpec#extensions-v0">
  <tp:copyright> Copyright © 2011 Collabora Limited </tp:copyright>
  <tp:license xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>This library is free software; you can redistribute it and/or
modify it under the terms of the GNU Lesser General Public
License as published by the Free Software Foundation; either
version 2.1 of the License, or (at your option) any later version.</p>

<p>This library is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the GNU
Lesser General Public License for more details.</p>

<p>You should have received a copy of the GNU Lesser General Public
License along with this library; if not, write to the Free Software
Foundation, Inc., 51 Franklin Street, Fifth Floor, Boston, MA 02110-1301, USA.</p>
  </tp:license>
  <interface name="com.meego.xpmn.ytstenut.Status">

    <tp:mapping name="Contact_Capability_Map">
      <tp:member type="s" name="Contact_Id">
        <tp:docstring>
          The contact for the device on which these capabilities are present.
        </tp:docstring>
      </tp:member>
      <tp:member type="a{sa{ss}}" name="Capability_Status_Info"
        tp:type="Capability_Service_Map">
        <tp:docstring>
          The advertised status of the various services, with capabilities
          available for this contact.
        </tp:docstring>
      </tp:member>
      <tp:docstring>
        A mapping of contacts to the capabilities, and status information
        advertised by each.
      </tp:docstring>
    </tp:mapping>

    <tp:mapping name="Capability_Service_Map">
      <tp:member type="s" name="Capability">
        <tp:docstring>
          The capability for which the status is being advertised.
        </tp:docstring>
      </tp:member>
      <tp:member type="a{ss}" name="Service_Status_Info"
        tp:type="Service_Status_Map">
        <tp:docstring>
          The advertized status of services that expose this capability.
        </tp:docstring>
      </tp:member>
      <tp:docstring>
        A mapping of capabilities to the status of the relevant services.
      </tp:docstring>
    </tp:mapping>

    <tp:mapping name="Service_Status_Map">
      <tp:member type="s" name="Service_Name">
        <tp:docstring>
          The name of the service which advertised this status.
        </tp:docstring>
      </tp:member>
      <tp:member type="s" name="Status_Body">
        <tp:docstring>
          The UTF-8 encoded XML body of the Ytstenut status.
        </tp:docstring>
      </tp:member>
      <tp:docstring>
        Holds Ytstenut status information advertised by a contact for a given
        capability.
      </tp:docstring>
    </tp:mapping>

    <method name="AdvertiseStatus" tp:name-for-bindings="Advertise_Status">
      <arg direction="in" name="Capability" type="s">
        <tp:docstring>
          The capability for which this status is being advertised.
        </tp:docstring>
      </arg>
      <arg direction="in" name="Service_Name" type="s">
        <tp:docstring>
          The name of the service advertising this capability.
        </tp:docstring>
      </arg>
      <arg direction="in" name="Status" type="s">
        <tp:docstring>
          The UTF-8 encoded XML of the Ytstenut status. If set to a blank
          string, then this method will clear any advertised status for this
          capability and service name.
        </tp:docstring>
      </arg>
      <tp:docstring>
        Advertise or clear a Ytstenut status.
      </tp:docstring>
    </method>

    <property name="DiscoveredStatuses" access="read" type="a{sa{sa{ss}}}"
      tp:type="Contact_Capability_Map" tp:name-for-bindings="Discovered_Statuses">
      <tp:docstring>
        All the Ytstenut Statuses that we've discovered on the local network.
        These are advertised by the various services on the various devices.
      </tp:docstring>
    </property>

    <signal name="StatusChanged" tp:name-for-bindings="Status_Changed">
      <arg name="Contact_Id" type="s">
        <tp:docstring>
          The contact for the device on which the status changed.
        </tp:docstring>
      </arg>
      <arg name="Capability" type="s">
        <tp:docstring>
          The capability for which the status changed.
        </tp:docstring>
      </arg>
      <arg name="Service_Name" type="s">
        <tp:docstring>
          The name of the service whose status changed.
        </tp:docstring>
      </arg>
      <arg name="Status" type="s">
        <tp:docstring>
          The UTF-8 encoded XML Ytstetus status, or a empty string if the status
          was cleared.
        </tp:docstring>
      </arg>
      <tp:docstring>
        This signal is emitted when we discover that a Ytstenut service has
        changed or cleared its status on one one of the devices on the local
        network. The <tp:member-ref>DiscoveredStatuses</tp:member-ref> property
        will have been updated before this signal is emitted.
      </tp:docstring>
    </signal>

    <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
      <p>This is a sidecar object on a connection manager, which allows
        Ytstenut services to expose their current status, such as name,
        state or other info to interested parties on the local ytstenut
        network.</p>

      <p>This object also keeps track of the various Ytstenut statuses
      which are advertised on the local network.</p>
    </tp:docstring>

    <tp:mapping name="Localized_Name_Map">
      <tp:member type="s" name="Language">
        <tp:docstring>
          The <a
          href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IETF_language_tag">IETF
          language tag</a> for the localization of the service name.
        </tp:docstring>
      </tp:member>
      <tp:member type="s" name="Name">
        <tp:docstring>
          The localized name.
        </tp:docstring>
      </tp:member>
      <tp:docstring>
        A map of language tags and their respective localization of
        the service name.
      </tp:docstring>
    </tp:mapping>

    <tp:mapping name="Service_Map">
      <tp:member type="s" name="Name">
        <tp:docstring>
          The service's unique identifier.
        </tp:docstring>
      </tp:member>
      <tp:member name="Service" type="(sa{ss}as)" tp:type="Service">
        <tp:docstring>
          The details of the service.
        </tp:docstring>
      </tp:member>
      <tp:docstring>
        A map of service name to its detail structure.
      </tp:docstring>
    </tp:mapping>

    <tp:struct name="Service">
      <tp:member type="s" name="Type">
        <tp:docstring>
          The type of the service, either "application" or
          "controller".
        </tp:docstring>
      </tp:member>
      <tp:member type="a{ss}" name="Localized_Name_Map"
        tp:type="Localized_Name_Map">
        <tp:docstring>
          A map of localized names of the service.
        </tp:docstring>
      </tp:member>
      <tp:member type="as" name="Capabilities">
        <tp:docstring>
          A list of capabilities the service has.
        </tp:docstring>
      </tp:member>
      <tp:docstring>
        A structure containing information about a Ytstenut service.
      </tp:docstring>
    </tp:struct>

    <property name="DiscoveredServices" access="read" type="a{s(sa{ss}as)}"
              tp:type="Service_Map" tp:name-for-bindings="Discovered_Services">
      <tp:docstring>
        All the Ytstenut services that we've discovered on the local
        network.
      </tp:docstring>
    </property>

  </interface>
</node>
